Worst case scenario for strategy, in
order for the strategy model to break, I
think something with Bitcoin needs to
break.
>> What causes the price drop?
>> You got $5 billion of volatility junkies
that are out there pumped that the price
of the stock is going down and they're
continuing to short it. There are
periods of time where it will
underperform. And a lot of people are
speculating like once these companies go
below one MN like they're not going to
be able to do things. Well, that's just
false. It's false because there if
you're the 400th largest publicly traded
company in the S&P 500 and you get
disrupted by AI and your stock falls and
you have no balance sheet because you
issued dividends and you did stock
buybacks, what do you do?
>> You're dead.
>> I look at MSTR very similarly to the way
I look at Bitcoin. And this is a
duration asset. I I want to hold this
for forever uh because I personally
believe this company is going to be the
largest company on the planet. I'm going
to ask you a question. What's the point
of holding an equity?
It's such a pleasure to have Jeff Walton
with us. Um, I actually personally met
him at the sailor party. We can talk
about that later. Hello.
>> Hello. How we doing?
>> We're doing great.
>> We're doing good.
>> It's so good to see you again.
>> Yeah, absolutely. Great to see you. So,
I remember we're at the party and we
were lining up to take pictures and you
and your lovely wife were behind me and
my mom and we started talking. What a
small world.
>> Yeah, absolutely. Absolutely.
>> I met um David Lynn at that party and
then we um later hosted two conferences
together. Oh, I feel like people who
went to that party
>> like they are just working on Bitcoin in
so many different aspect and it was such
a beautiful thing what mailor did.
>> Yeah. Yeah. It's it's really inspiring,
isn't it? And uh I went into that party
knowing that I was going to quit my job
too. So, it was one of these like
amazing moments to be able to lean in
and see this is what the opportunity is
and and meet people and talk to people
that are operating and working in the
space and yeah, it was an amazing event.
>> When you talk about quitting job, can
can you tell us the story? What was the
transition?
>> Yeah, so I was uh working in
reinsurance. I was a reinsurance broker.
So, I sold insurance to insurance
companies and I did that for 11 years.
Okay. uh so it's a very niche area of
the capital markets. What I did is I I
effectively looked at an insurance
company's balance sheet and I identified
areas of volatility and I would sell
those pieces of volatility to global
diversified
uh insurance companies, hedge funds and
capital providers. And it it was a slog.
I I I worked, you know, really long
hours, late nights, did a lot of
marketing and traveling, going to see
different capital providers and uh
you're really subject to the the
industry environment and the macro
environment and it was really difficult.
I was just working harder and harder and
harder and I wasn't going any like
further in my career. Mhm.
>> I was finding new opportunities and
working on interesting things, but I I
saw a lot of issues in the industry in
the capital space uh that could be fixed
or addressed with Bitcoin.
>> Name one
>> long duration liabilities. So, um health
care costs.
>> If you've got uh a worker's
compensation, somebody slips and falls
and you've got to pay for their health
care for 10 years. If your assumption on
the cost of that health care is off by
25 basis points,
your whole business model is upside
down.
>> And they the insurance industries
themselves, they they hold assets to
meet future liabilities
and they have no ability to get Bitcoin
exposure. They they get zero credit from
the rating agencies if to if they hold
Bitcoin.
>> Mhm. which is the the primary hedge that
they need to protect against these, you
know, long-term liabilities. So, that
was one of the big problems and
challenges I was seeing in the industry,
aside from the fact that most of the
industry laughed at me when I brought up
the concept of Bitcoin.
>> And uh I I saw a lot of opportunity in
the space. So, I quit my job in February
and wanted to deploy my energy towards
Bitcoin somehow. I didn't know exactly
how. I was like looking at different
opportunities and exploring different
things.
>> Luckily, my investment in Micro Strategy
put me in a place where I felt
comfortable taking taking time and
observing the landscape and
>> figuring out what was best for me. And
that was where the opportunity with
Strive came up and now the VP of Bitcoin
strategy at Strive. And
>> congratulations.
>> Thank you. and uh looking at running the
strategy playbook and identifying
opportunities in the capital space to
keep you know pushing forward and uh in
this corporate adoption of Bitcoin and
securitizing Bitcoin and uh operating a
bitcoin treasury strategy.
>> Michael Sailor is such a genius. He he
came up with all these different
products. You are very familiar with all
of his product. He used to use a lot of
convertible bonds,
>> but this year 2025, it's the year of
preferred stock.
>> Perpetual preferred stock.
>> Exactly.
>> Mhm.
>> It sounds scary. It's like forever. You
got to pay dividends forever. Can you
break it down for us? How is that better
than CBS?
>> If you just think about the concept of
the debt,
>> uh, a convertible bond has a maturity.
So, let's just say you take on $2
billion of debt. um at a future point in
time, let's say the duration is four
years, six years, or eight years, you've
got to pay back that $2 billion
maturity.
>> With the convertibles, they have the
ability to convert into equity. So, you
know, there's there's a little bit less
risk on on that side when looking at a
convertible bond. But the really unique
nature here of a perpetual preferred
liability is that there's no there is no
maturity. So, if you have a balance
sheet that's growing at, you know, 50%
compound annual growth rate and you're
lending out uh capital at 9%, there's a
huge arbitrage opportunity between the
compound annual growth rate of the asset
you hold on your balance sheet and the
liability that you're paying out into
the future.
>> The fixed dividend is about 8 to 10%,
right?
>> Yeah. So, the perpetual preferred equity
instruments themselves have a fixed
dollar denominated dividend. It's not a
percentage dividend when when they were
issued. Uh they're issued at at a
percentage, right? So at par, um STRF
pays $10 per share. PAR is $100. So it's
effectively 10% dividend. Now
that it it's $10 per share. So to the
extent that there's debasement of the
currency, that $10 per share is actually
uh it's becoming less and less valuable
over time and into the future. This is a
this is a onedirection trade. This is uh
USD for Bitcoin swap sort of thing. Um
the the biggest innovation
in these instruments is that they are
they're using the position in the
capital stack as collateral. Okay. What
does that mean? That means uh the the
seniority
of where the capital sits within the
capital stack is a function of the risk
profile of it.
>> Mhm.
>> And this is this is a a concept, right?
This is a this is a broader concept. So
in the event of a bankruptcy or
liquidation, this is what this whole
thing kind of relies on. In the event of
a bankruptcy or liquidation, those
holders of equity or debt get paid out
first. So if you think of convertible
bond holders are most senior. So if
there's a liquidation the convertible
bond holders get paid out their their m
their notional value.
>> Uh the next person in line for money is
STRF holders. They would get paid out
next and then STRC and then STRK and
then STRD and then M if there's any
money left it goes to the MSTR
shareholders generally in like
bankruptcy situations.
um the equity is generally worthless
>> and the capital is really just going out
to the bond holders. So the innovation
here is that they've
collateralized different risk tunches
within the capital stack and and this is
just theoretical right the if the the
STRF product is the most senior product.
So this you could think of this as the
investment grade product meaning it's
the furthest away from risk. M
>> and so that that positioning has created
this effective like risk curve of
getting Bitcoin like exposure
>> but understanding that you have the
protection of seniority in the capital
stack.
>> It has nothing to do with Bitcoin
though. I'm I'm expecting a fixed pay
payout, you know, annually. How how does
that you know how do you call that
Bitcoin related?
>> Yeah. So the the the unique thing here
is any capital that's coming in the door
on any of those instruments is going to
buy Bitcoin immediately. They're adding
Bitcoin to the balance sheet. So So
you've got this Bitcoin balance sheet
that's continuing to grow,
>> right?
>> Okay. So that that is collateral like
>> that is the collateral and the value
that is backing uh any of these
instruments that they have within the
capital stack. Mhm.
>> So what what gives you that Bitcoin like
exposure if you buy any of these
instruments? The Bitcoin-l like exposure
is the fact that they are paying a
higher yield than any other product
product in the market. They have less
risk than any other product in the
market. They are more liquid than any
other product in the market. And when
when you start to put all of these
components together and you compare it
to other fixed income instruments in the
market, these become an outlier very
quickly and they become too good not to
hold.
>> Yeah.
>> And and that's one of the things that's
just so incredibly appealing to me.
These are these products are so good.
>> Yeah. that they are going to be in every
pension fund, every insurance company,
every fixed income holder at at a future
point in time because they are they they
are so productive uh in a portfolio.
>> Help me understand this. When when it
was CBS
>> um MSTR actually has to pay close to no
no interest
>> and basically it was free money to buy
Bitcoin. But now this sounds very
expensive.
>> Yeah. Why
>> the the relativity? So, uh that that's a
that's a really good question and re
really they were they were given 0%
interest rate debt but the interest rate
was priced into the conversion premium.
>> Oh.
>> So, so interest rates and the conversion
premium those are those are two levers
that you can pull to uh to create a
transaction. So it it was more
accreative for strategy to say I'll give
you a higher conversion premium just
give me 0% interest. So that that was a
great opportunity for them.
>> Um but you you look at some of the
conversion premiums I 45% or 55% and
that becomes that's
>> that's an that's an expense that's
another way to look at it. Whereas if
they were to take you know six seven or
8% interest maybe the conversion premium
would be 35%. M
>> so those are two those are two mechanics
that can work uh opposite direction of
each other. So really when you and the
other the other component that's
interesting with convertible bonds and
one of the reasons I think they've kind
of fallen out of flavor a little bit
it's it's a capital market that's open
for um these types of transactions. The
market is relatively small though.
>> I think it's a under a trillion dollar
market. if you needed to go raise
capital cheaply, quickly, and easily,
like that is a market that you can go
to.
But the uh the bigger unlock here is
unlocking a much larger pool of capital.
So, how do I attract, you know, the $300
or $300 trillion fixed income market,
>> you need to go fishing with the right
hook,
>> you know, you need the right lure and
the the fixed income market isn't going
to buy the convertible bonds. you need
to give them a product that they can
consume that looks like everything else
that they have in their portfolio.
>> So when when you think about the this
this concept of of expensive, it's it's
not very expensive when you look at the
productivity of the asset that you're
acquiring in exchange for that.
>> So and if you look at the entire capital
stack too, right? I mean to put this in
perspective and this is something a lot
of people aren't aware of. I mean,
Strategy is holding $70 billion worth of
Bitcoin. Maybe 75. It's between 70 and
$75 billion worth of Bitcoin. The
dividend liability that they have
annually is $600 million.
So, uh, one thing that I I like to do
and try to put this into perspective
because these are huge numbers. They're
like hard to wrap your head around for
for most people.
>> And, um, one way I like to look at it is
I like to, you know, chop some zeros
off. Okay. So
the the one of the reasons this entire
thing works is because strategy has so
much financial strength that they have a
continuous ability to go raise capital
in different markets and going to raise
capital in different markets helps pay
off these dividends or you know go buy
more Bitcoin or the flexibility to move
however they need to. And I like to put
this into perspective. Imagine you're a
um you you have $7 million of assets in
your investment portfolio and you need a
$60,000 loan to go get a house.
>> Easy.
>> If you're an underwriter, you'd say,
"Absolutely. I'll underwrite that risk
all day. That's a great risk. Let's take
it further. Let's say the Bitcoin falls
50%. Now you've got $3.5 million
relative to a $60,000 loan. Would you
underwrite that loan?"
>> Absolutely. you you'd say absolutely. So
that their their ability to raise
capital is a function of their financial
strength which is which is how this
whole thing continues to work. They're
able to raise additional capital at
terms that are attractive and accreative
that they can go buy Bitcoin or you know
do other treasury operations that they
deem and see fit
>> from what you're saying. So, I thought
the reason why they kind of paused this
CB um route is because they don't want
to dilute their shareholder too much,
but it's because they want to access
their a different pool of capital.
>> It's accessing a different pool of
capital. It's also accessing a different
holder.
>> Uh so, the convertible bond
uh sellers, the people that are selling
this product,
>> they don't care about the stock at all.
>> They they are volatility junkies. So
they want the opportunity to arb the
delta between the convertible bond price
and the value of the equity that sits
beneath it. So there's infinite
arbitrage opportunities back and forth
between uh the inefficiencies in the
convertible bond market and the equity
market and how they're priced. So
they're constantly shorting the stock,
they're constantly buying the stock,
they're constantly shorting the stock.
Additionally, the the convertible bond
sellers when strategy issues the
convertible bond, they sell about 70% of
the notional value short immediately on
day one to hedge their position.
>> So, you could think about the dilution
uh the the dilution impact happens on
day one. It occurs on day one. Now you
think about the difference in these new
perpetual preferred instruments and if
if they need to issue MSDR common stock
in order to pay the dividend now that
dilution is is happening over time.
>> You you know it's a it's a different
horizon. Additionally the the people
that hold those instruments they want
them for the yield and the risk
protection not for the volatility. They
want it for the lack of volatility. So
the the buyer of those in of those
products,
>> who are they?
>> Uh it's retail, it's institutions, it's
insurance companies, it's pension funds,
>> they're they're long these instruments,
not long volatility. Mhm.
>> And and that's a a fundamental
difference and a more beneficial
uh person to have in your capital
structure than somebody that's, you
know, taking advantage of the volatility
of your common stock. So there there's
and a $300 trillion pool of capital,
right? It's it's an enormous pool of
capital and they have the ability to um
create products that are attractive in
that in that marketplace. for a regular
investor. I don't I don't think most
people understand every bit, you know.
>> Yeah, it's complicated.
>> It's super complicated. They just hold
MSTR
>> and if you go back and you look at since
they started the Bitcoin Treasury
Strategy,
>> they are they are, you know, three to
four times uh levered the return of
Bitcoin. There are periods of time where
it it will underperform and you could
see this in the marketplace where there
are now new people that are coming into
the market saying I'm shorting strategy
because I don't think this premium
should exist or you know that there's a
lot of people that are using this
instrument to trade in different
directions in different different ways
and different places over the long term.
I think the most important and valuable
metric here is Bitcoin per share. Mhm.
>> It's like, well, if you're using fiat to
to denominate the the return of this
instrument, you're you're taking a fiat
lens to this um this instrument to begin
with. So, the way I look at it, I look
at MSTR very similarly to the way I look
at Bitcoin, and this is a this is a long
this is a duration asset. I I want to
hold this for forever.
uh because I personally believe this
company is going to be the largest
company on the planet and I don't want
to be in a position where I have to tell
my grandchildren that I sold MSTR at,
you know, $400
>> uh when, you know, 10 20 years from now
it's $20,000 or $30,000 a share or
something like that. And um I I've had
many of these experiences in in my life
with family members saying, "Oh, I could
have bought Apple at 89." And well, it's
like, well, you didn't you didn't buy
Apple at 89 cents and you wouldn't have
had the conviction to hold it anyway.
So, like
>> uh the
>> it's and there's this Sailor interview
where he's uh talking about his friends
that are talking about buying and
selling Google between a dollar and
a$150 and he's like shaking was like
what are you doing? like uh this is this
is all this is fundamentally changing
humanity and this is changing the world
and uh you've got to take a long-term
view view on these um specific products
and instruments. So there's a lot of
people, you know, making a lot of noise
about this stuff because the stock, you
know, had this epic blowoff top. It hit
$543 in November of last year. uh just
straight parabola in you know a month of
time and since then has gone through
this like choppy chop consolidation
period where there's a a new floor being
set on the
>> is it because people lose conviction or
what what causes the price drop
>> it's so many things I mean there there
are so many people trading in the
marketplace it's a function of the
underlying uh bitcoin being held it's
the convertible bond holders I mean
there's five $5 billion of convertible
bond that are not trading like equity in
the market. So you've got $5 billion of
volatility junkies that are out there
pumped that the price of the stock is
going down and they're continuing to
short it.
>> I see.
>> So they are making money by shorting the
stock.
>> Yeah. And that that's that's I I think
one of the reasons that uh strategies
kind of pivoted on convertible bonds
because they they've seen the um the
effects of issuing that much of this
type of instrument in a in a very short
time horizon.
>> When we talk about perpetual preferred
stock, can they ever buy it back? Like
stop paying the dividend
>> on all of the instruments right now. I
don't believe there's a call on on any
of them.
>> That is crazy. Like think about
investing $10 and get $1 every every
year. Like that is insane.
>> Yeah. But if if your if the value of
your dollar drops 90% in 10 years, then
I mean
>> true.
>> Well, it's like you're getting $10, but
well, $10 is going to be equivalent to
$1 10 years from now.
>> So, do I
>> it's a great instrument for now. And
where where I think these products have
a really good opportunity in the
marketplace right now is like retirement
accounts. Mhm.
>> So, you've got people that are near
retirement and they they want a little
extra juice in their income that they're
making uh to help, you know, to help
them manage their retirement. These
products are really really appealing.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh and if the horizon of your life is
another 20 years,
>> you're not too worried about
>> you're not too worried about it, right?
And you're not too worried about the
debasement of your currency for the rest
of your life. you're you're more worried
about just enjoying your life for the
last 20 years or or whatever that may
be.
>> For me, I'm interested in the perpetual
preferred instruments
>> from the understanding that I think
they're mispriced and I think they're
going to be repriced.
>> And there are other people that are
buying it for the yield. There are other
people that are um you know, speculating
on you X Y or Z. But um I'm not buying
it for the reduced volatility.
I where I'm at in my life, like my age,
like I want full V right now. I I want
all of the volatility because I have
supreme conviction and I know where this
is going directionally. So that's the
way I I view it.
>> What about all the other Bitcoin
treasury companies? They're are copying
the same strategy, but are they going to
perform the same? I think that's a
that's a great question and and I think
there's a lot of opportunity for these
Bitcoin treasury companies in this space
uh to continue to grow and buy more
Bitcoin perpetually into the future
whether that be through cash flow or
capital markets opportunities uh that a
lot of people are speculating like once
these companies go below one MV like
they're not going to be able to do
things. Well, that's just false, right?
>> Why is that false? It's false because
they're sitting on capital
>> and it depends on the value of that
capital, the leverage on the balance
sheet, how they're managing the leverage
on the balance sheet. But you can always
get a deal done like if if you needed to
um let let's just say let's just say to
make the numbers easy, let's just say
you're holding a billion dollars of
Bitcoin and you've got um you know
hund00 million of leverage. So you're
10% leverage uh but the value of your
stock is trading at like $700 million
market cap or something like that. So
like a.7 M&A, you can go to the capital
markets with your billion dollars of
Bitcoin and go like identify leverage
opportunities to go leverage up your
balance sheet a little bit more and buy
more Bitcoin.
>> Um alternatively, you could be in a
situation where it it may make more
sense to sell a little piece of your
Bitcoin to buy your stock back.
>> Do you think strategy would ever do
that? because that's more like a
conviction like fake. You're not
supposed to.
>> Yeah. I It would be a break glass
scenario. I I think it's incredibly
unlikely. Yeah.
>> Um but the another reason this entire
thing works is because the threat is
there,
>> right? Like Bitcoin is the most liquid
instrument on the planet. You could go
you you watch Nakamoto went and bought a
million dollars a minute to buy $750
million. You you can do that. Like the
market is incredibly liquid. they could
go buy and sell as much as they need to
and like get pretty efficient uh
settlement and efficient pricing with it
because it it's just so liquid. So that
that threat to be able to do that is
always there. But that there are so many
other things you can do, right? You can
you can sell covered calls, you could go
access perpetual preferred debt, you
could go get straight debt, you can go
get convertible debt and and it's all a
function of your the under underlying
collateral that you have in the balance
sheet. It doesn't like whatever the
stock's doing. It doesn't really matter
if it's trading at a premium. You can
access the equity market and you could
go issue ATM to raise capital that way.
But uh in in distressed situations,
distressed, it may be more efficient to
go tackle capital in different places or
just wait.
>> You could just wait. If you are
directionally long Bitcoin and you think
the the the market is going to move
favorably with you and you understand
the landscape, you're like, "Okay,
strategy is working for me. Semilar's
working for me. Uh MARA is working for
me." like all you go look at all of the
Bitcoin treasury companies that are look
their whole goal is to accumulate as
much Bitcoin as humanly possible. You
could just wait
>> because the the likelihood that all of
them are are not doing anything is zero.
Uh so I I think it's imperative
uh I I think having Bitcoin on your
balance sheet is going to be imperative
for the future. And if if you look at
the landscape of u like equity mark
equity capital markets and like all of
these companies that are trading on
these different exchanges, they're
significantly exposed to AI disruption.
>> Mhm.
>> And if those companies get disrupted by
AI, what can you do?
>> Explain that.
>> So, so like I just mentioned right here,
right? Like if your equity falls and you
still hold this Bitcoin, at least you
hold the Bitcoin. You could go do
something with it. you're like, I could
go leverage it to go buy a company or I
could go do X or, you know, go issue
debt and go buy more Bitcoin. Like,
what? You could do so many things.
>> But if you're a if you're the 400th
largest publicly traded company in the
S&P 500 and you get disrupted by AI and
your stock falls and you have no balance
sheet because you issued dividends and
you did stock buybacks, what do you do?
You're dead. You're dead. Unless you had
Bitcoin on your balance sheet. So I I I
truly believe that there's going to be a
huge turnover in the S&P 500 and these
other large indices as AI does disrupt
and a lot of these companies are dead in
the water without any without a strong
balance sheet to be able to operate in
the marketplace. So, it's kind of a a
fiat problem. Like the one of the reason
one of the reasons we're in this
situation is because uh everybody's been
like chasing this like cash dividend
stock buyback cash dividend stock
buyback and there's been less emphasis
on uh balance sheet strength and ability
to manage different market environments
and and I think I think that will change
drastically. But the counterargument
would be the other companies, the tech
companies you talk about, they are
producing a product that's helping
humanity, but what are you guys doing,
right? You guys are just buying Bitcoin,
blah blah blah. What would you say to
them?
>> They're producing a product that's
helping humanity or they're they're
improving the value of a product that's
helping humanity. How many people hold
Bitcoin?
>> I don't know, like 30 30 million. 30
million people hold Bitcoin. M
>> seems like a pretty good product with a
lot of people that that hold it and
you've got a huge total addressable
market of people that could hold it too.
>> Uh additionally like the the instruments
and the securities that strategy has
created and these other Bitcoin treasury
companies will create will help humanity
>> like this is solving a a huge retirement
gap in the United States and and other
places on the planet. it. This will
provide a significant
low volatility return instrument for
people that need it. And that's
the biggest market on the planet. The
like the the total addressable market of
the space is like $600 trillion.
The total addressable market for Apple
is like I don't know three trillion,
four trillion, five trillion maybe. And
they're like bumping up against that
that valuation right now. They're like
$3 trillion company. I think it's a bit
misunderstood.
>> Uh the equity product itself is also a a
valuable product. Like if you think of
these different countries like
MetaPlanet like I wasn't able to get
Bitcoin exposure but now I can get
Bitcoin exposure via an equity in my
pension fund
>> uh in Japan. that's a product.
People are
lost by not recognizing that's also
itself is not a problem.
>> I think people are so focused on the
story the reason why they convert
themselves into a Bitcoin treasury
company. They're like, "Oh, it's just
because you you were trying to save your
company. This is just a method for you
to save your company instead of thinking
how this product could benefit me."
Right. As an investor.
>> Yeah. So, so I'm going to ask I'm going
to ask you a question. What's the point
of holding an equity? Any equity.
>> To keep my purchasing power.
>> Bingo. Store of value.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay. Well, what's a better store of
value than a company that has value?
Like what what's a what's a better store
of value than a company that holds more
store of value than any other company on
the planet?
>> Mhm. What about the smaller Bitcoin
treasury companies? They have supposedly
a bigger upside because they're small.
>> Yeah.
>> How should people look at it?
>> That they all have a different risk
return metric.
>> So, so different different risk return
profile at different points in time too,
right? And this this conversation is
evolving and everybody's trying to
figure it out at the same time. Like one
of the couple of the metrics people are
looking at is like
>> Bitcoin yield, what is MNAV? What is
months to cover MNAV? They're like
people are creating these new metrics uh
that are trying to wrap their head
around like a a new risk return profile
for these instruments because at any
point in time one of uh you know one of
the smaller Bitcoin treasury companies
may be may look more risky relative to a
different one.
>> Yeah.
>> Maybe the MNAV is high. Maybe at that
point it's ris it's more risky than a
company that's got it a low MNAV and
maybe they flip
>> and you know there's different points of
time where things have
>> may look a cheap or maybe look rich
relative to each other. So there's this
new risk profile that's being created on
all these all of these different
instruments, but they all provide
different risk return upside. So I I see
the world in in terms of like
probabilistic distributions and uh like
risk curves. So uh there is a there is
an efficient frontier of having any one
of these different instruments in in a
diversified bundle of baskets to to
maximize your return and minimize your
risk. Obviously, strategy is the
enormous player in the space, and I
don't think anybody's going to catch
them, which puts them in a in a whole
new echelon of risk return, right? It's
it's the lowest risk out of all of the
other uh companies because they have the
biggest balance sheet and relatively
small amount of leverage. Where there's
other companies that may be leaning a
little bit more heavily into leverage,
>> which is risky, right? If the if the
price of the Bitcoin falls and they're
unable to meet their liabilities, they
may be in a point where they have to get
liquidated or somebody buys them or you
know you are taking different risks on
any of these different companies.
>> What's your thought on Ethereum Treasury
Company?
>> Would you rather build your house on
sand or build your house on a rock?
>> I don't know. You tell me.
>> Uh look, look, I I think Ethereum's
going to be around for a long time. Mhm.
>> There are going to be companies that are
going to capitalize their balance sheet
on Ethereum rather than Bitcoin.
When you're operating in the capital
markets, I think if you're going to
raise capital, whether it be equity
capital, debt capital,
it's much easier to explain the story of
Bitcoin as a $2.5 trillion asset rather
than the story of Ethereum, which is a
$500 billion asset on your balance
sheet. So,
>> I I think companies that are going to
succeed in the digital asset treasury
space, I think they're going to have a a
lot easier of a time interfacing with
traditional capital with a Bitcoin
treasury than any other digital
treasury.
>> So, you're looking at it from like a
numbers perspective, but a lot of people
are looking at it uh they're they're
talking about POS versus P.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. the pro proof of stake,
proof of work. I mean, I I'm a I'm a
proof of work maxi. I'm a Bitcoin maxi.
Uh, you know, I I explored NFTTS on
Ethereum just because I I thought it was
interesting and fun and and like that
space is going to exist. Like there's a
there's a different utility with
Ethereum than there is for Bitcoin. And
for me, I I again coming from a finance
background working in the reinsurance
market and seeing like the world of
capital and how it works, the companies
that are based with a Bitcoin treasury
are going to have a easier time in the
traditional capital markets, which is a
much bigger pool of capital. At the
moment, there are no Ethereum treasury
companies that have perpetual preferred
instruments that they could go offer to
the market. I mean, you go look at Bit
Miner, Tom Le's deal. I think they've
got a $6 billion market cap. If they
were go to go issue perpetual preferred
equity to the market, they would be able
to issue maybe two billion
>> if they could find it. You'd have to go
convince somebody that it's a good idea
and then you got to go find the capital
and then get it. So, all right. Now, the
company's a $6 billion company goes to
an $8 billion company. The scale like
the numbers the numbers aren't in favor
of an Ethereum treasury company. The the
numbers are in favor of Bitcoin treasury
companies and their their ability to
access different pools of capital. Let's
go back to Bitcoin companies. People
talk about if you want to buy a stock,
you look at the founder. That founder
has to be a true Bitcoiner and promise
not to sell. But there are a lot of
people here just for the hype. How do
you tell?
>> Yeah. I guess the question is what what
is a what is a true Bitcoiner? I mean,
Bitcoin's for everyone.
>> That's a good that's a good answer.
>> Like what is a true Bitcoiner? Like you
could anybody could do anything.
>> I can say, okay, let's say I start this
company and I claim to be a Bitcoin
treasury company. I tell the world that
I'm going to follow strategy strategy.
However, I exit once my stock pump. That
is not a true Bitcoiner.
>> Yeah. No, that that sounds like a
fraudster just in general. But uh but
there's always break glass scenarios
like that. There's again I see the world
in probabilistic distributions and I I
think there there could be a point in
time where you may strategically look to
sell covered calls on Bitcoin or uh you
know sell a sliver to buy the stock
back. It's an optionality like having
this asset on your balance sheet is
providing you know maximum optionality.
Now in terms of being able to identify
whether somebody's a true Bitcoin maxi
and willing to uh and not going to run
away with your cash or do anything like
that I mean that's just the risk of
buying equity. There is an element of
trust
>> in buying any equity buying any other
security or any instrument. There is an
there's a huge element of trust. So, you
got to be able to trust the people that
uh are operating the business that
you're like buying buying stock in. But
ultimately, I think everybody should
self-custody Bitcoin. And we we we
preach that all the time on True North
and in the with in the people that I
talk to. It's hard to have conviction in
any of these equities unless you
self-custody Bitcoin and you see the
true power of, you know, having
sovereignty with assets, being able to
like walk around the block with $10,000
in your pocket, right? It's a huge
innovation and I think that's
foundational in anybody's portfolio is
to have this you know Bitcoin and
self-custody before before you start
exploring any of these other things
because if you go dump all your money
into a Bitcoin asset or Bitcoin treasury
company and they the founder goes and
runs away with all your money it's like
well if they did that you better have
some Bitcoin
>> right so that that's kind of that's kind
of how I view it and a a lot of people
are mad at strategy because the stock
hasn't gone up Mhm.
>> And it's like, well, how long have you
held it?
>> How long should I hold it?
>> I I I think everybody should look at uh
these companies as longterm
uh long-term holds, like fouryear
fouryear plus holds. If you look at
Bitcoin itself, if you look at every
single four-year compound annual growth
rate period of Bitcoin, they're all
positive. the 99.5 99.5 percentile of
four-year Bitcoin compound annual growth
rates is something like 26%. So
that's like the the worst point4%. If
you bought Bitcoin on the worst possible
day and sold it on the worst possible
day four years later, your the worst
compound annual growth rate is like 22%.
Like that's, you know, like you you gota
you got to be willing to sit on these
things and and I think that concept is
really rewriting corporate finance in
general. Like strategy just posted a $10
billion net income in Q2.
>> Huge just like just blowout net income.
And you compare it to like any of these
other companies and it's just like
>> all these other companies are tiny. But
the commentary in the market is this is
a one-time game.
M
>> but when you when you actually zoom out
and you take a look at it and let's just
say you averaged their net income over
the last four years. Well, their average
net income over the last four years
annually is like $5 billion per year.
>> Insane
>> on on average, right? And you start to
compare that to like these other
companies that are averaging, you know,
$2 billion of net income annually and
like the numbers start to get pretty
wonky really quick. And there's a lot of
short-timerism in the existing equity
markets which I think is a function of
fiat where like every every analyst,
every equity market, every algorithm is
like quickly trading based on uh quarter
overquarter results and guidance and
year-over-year results when I think more
broadly companies should be looking at
like long-term trends and investors
should be looking at long-term trends,
four-year trends, uh AI trends, computer
trends,
uh data and information trends, those
kinds of things.
>> Um especially if the whole goal is to
store value like as as we talked about
it's the point of equity
>> uh to store value and uh so I think a
long-term perspective on any of these
things is uh the most efficient and
appropriate way to go.
>> There are two different ways to you know
accumulate Bitcoin. One group of
investors they want to time the market.
They want to buy when it's low. And the
sailor group or I assume you do that too
is DCA. You you don't time the market.
You always buy the top because like you
said if you look at long-term it's not
going to be that much different. Which
strategy should I use to buy strategy?
Is it the DCA method or because it's so
volatile should I time the market?
>> Yeah. I I don't see why you wouldn't
look at it very similarly to Bitcoin. So
DCA
>> I I I think ultimately for for 99.9% of
people the answer is going to be like DC
DCA a way in or or like get get some
like greater than 0% exposure. If if you
don't have any exposure to these Bitcoin
treasury companies, you're short Bitcoin
treasury companies.
>> Same as Bitcoin, right? Like if you
don't have any exposure to Bitcoin,
you're short Bitcoin.
>> I don't want to be short Bitcoin.
>> And uh that's that's kind of the way I I
look at it. It's like having greater
than 0% exposure is what I what I want
to have and uh lean into that.
>> Why wouldn't you just hold Bitcoin then?
Because that is the fundamental of the
whole strategy.
>> Yeah, that's an answer for a lot of
people may not have conviction in the
space or they just want exposure to the
underlying commodity like that is a that
is a great answer for most people. Now
other people want more high octane
exposure. So you can get more high
octane exposure by buying a leveraged
Bitcoin equity like strategy or any of
these Bitcoin treasury companies. Or you
can get lower octane exposure uh like
buying strike or strife or stride or any
of these you know perpetual preferred
instruments. And again, I I see that
there was this there was this
foundational um
innovation in finance called Marowitz's
modern portfolio theory. And I I hit on
this a little bit earlier, but it won
the Nobel Prize in economics actually.
And the the concept is uh if you have a
diversified portfolio with various
different risk return metrics, you can
increase the return of your portfolio
and reduce the risk of your portfolio.
So,
Bitcoin has a different risk return
metric than strategy.
>> Uh, you know, any other Bitcoin treasury
company has a different risk return
metric as well. So, if you have greater
than 0% exposure, it should elevate
uh elevate the return and reduce the
risk of the portfolio. Now, that being
said, if you have everything in your
port portfolio correlated to Bitcoin,
that is that is a risk in and of itself.
But personally for me where I see
Bitcoin's future and where Bitcoin's
going in the uh in the long term I'm
okay personally that uh that level of
exposure.
>> You hold a lot of MSTR, right?
>> Yes.
>> Worst case scenario, I'm trying to think
of the worst case scenario. What
happens? What would happen and what
would that scenario look like?
>> Like worst case scenario for strategy.
>> Mhm. Nightmare.
>> Yeah. I I mean a lot of people are
trying to conceptualize this as well and
I I made a post about this last night
actually funny enough in in order for
the strategy model to break I think
something with Bitcoin needs to break
>> for example
>> hard to hard to conceptualize but like
global EMP
>> oh
>> you know the internet like
>> the internet should
>> but it's not a strategy problem anymore
if that happens
>> right and and so when when I think of
like these probabilistic scenarios of a
of a situation where the fundamentals of
Bitcoin breaks or
all of a sudden all of these companies
don't start buy like stop buying Bitcoin
for whatever reason.
>> Uh are they determined that another
asset is a stronger store of value?
>> I think that's incredibly unlikely. If
that happens, then you know there are a
lot of people that are in the Bitcoin
space. They've got to figure out
something else and go go do something
else. And um I think that's that's kind
of what it looks like. I I think there's
a higher probability of the Yellowstone
Caldera exploding
uh than like Bitcoin breaking.
>> I see.
>> Like uh so when I think of that scenario
like Yellowstone Caldera, it's like okay
well I'm dead anyway. So that that
outcome is zero.
>> Um and you think of a probability
scenario where Bitcoin breaks think of
that's a low probability and the outcome
is zero. Like that's also zero.
>> So uh
>> nothing related to strategy. It's all
Bitcoin. Yeah, I I I really I really
don't think so. I mean, there there are
tail scenarios that are they're black
swan tail scenarios that people can't
think of uh that that exist like black
swans always exist. Um is there keyman
risk a little bit? Yeah, there's
probably a little bit of keyman risk
with Sailor, but that they're already
working on like Fong is incredibly
powerful and strong, very great
communicator. He's getting out into the
market a bit more. M
>> um even even if Sailor were gone,
>> the the company's still got $70 billion
worth of Bitcoin. They've got 3% of the
network. Like the the company will
continue to operate uh into the future,
>> right?
>> Um not being able to pay your
liabilities at some point in the future.
Again,
>> you look at the balance sheet, they've
got 10% leverage. uh they're incredibly
strong relative to their interest that
they they could pay 120 years of the
dividend liability with their Bitcoin
right now,
>> right? So like most of the market is
asking them to take on more leverage,
you know, and so they're trying to add
it on as quickly as possible. So like
with where they're at right now, I have
like the least amount of concern
>> for the longevity of the company and the
ability for them to continue to operate.
>> Let's talk about you. What do you do at
Strive? Yeah. So, Strive, I I am the VP
of Bitcoin strategy. So, I am
>> helping think through our Bitcoin
strategy.
>> I'm gonna wear a lot of hats. And this
company is is going to be flexible in
the in the capital markets, going to
identify different pools of capital and
different opportunity to add Bitcoin to
the balance sheet. Some of the things
I'm thinking about right now are um how
do we communicate to the market and and
how do we identify and structure our
leverage, our future leverage? Um what
we want to do is we want to buy Bitcoin
and we we want to leverage the Bitcoin
to buy more Bitcoin. That's the general
theme of most of these Bitcoin treasury
companies. So I'm thinking about how do
how do we leverage how do we communicate
leverage? Um how do we communicate that
story to the capital markets too? And
and I that's where I I think I can take
some of the background that I've built
with the True North team and be able to
relay that same type of message into the
larger broader capital markets similar
to what I did in the reinsurance world.
Like when I was in reinsurance, I sold
volatility to uh risk-taking investment
managers. Now that's the same exact
thing with Bitcoin. I'm going to go sell
like reduced volatility instruments to
capital providers and I've got to be
able to tell that story. Why is it a
good product? It's a good product
because it's got lower volatility than
Bitcoin. Um, it's got higher liquidity
than Bitcoin. What is the risk? Kind of
outline the risk profile. So, taking a a
risk lens and being able to communicate
that to the broader capital markets and
like the retail market and continue to,
you know, help that help that story.
Additionally, it's finding opportunity
within the different capital markets and
and thinking through, you know, that
that broader just general general
Bitcoin strategy. The company is full of
uh financeers, so people with different
diverse backgrounds. I mean, led by CEO
Matt Cole, who ran a $70 billion fixed
income
portfolio at Kalpers. Kalpers is uh the
pension fund for California which is
like the largest pension fund in the
planet. As you can imagine having it
somebody with a massive fixed income
background
going into the market and looking at you
know issuing fixed income bitcoin backed
fixed income securities. There's there's
a lot of benefit and things that we can
think about and creativity that we can
use in that marketplace. Uh
and be a little bit more nimble than
strategy. Like Strategy is uh
again like the the 600 pound gorilla in
the space, right? They're enormous. And
Strategy's goal is they they want to
bring in $3 trillion of capital into
Bitcoin over time in the fixed income
market. If you're going to bring if
you're going to bring in $3 trillion of
capital, you need to be so incredibly
transparent and like your story needs to
be so incredibly clean. The market needs
to trust that you're going to be able to
manage and hold that amount of capital.
the smaller companies can be a little
bit more flexible and nimble and they're
going to be like operating around the
edges and finding opportunity that may
be a little too small for strategy.
>> Um, and it might be opportunity for us
to be like the Lamborghini within the
Bitcoin treasury space that maybe maybe
moves a little bit faster in both
directions. Um, but because we can be a
little bit more flexible with our our
capital structure.
>> How do you come up with different
strategies? Do you sit in a meeting room
and everybody just starts, I don't know,
throwing out ideas? How does that work?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Well, uh, late night phone
calls, uh, like, um, you know, sitting
on sitting on the couch going for a
walk. Uh, there's multiple times where
Matt Matt Kohl's called me. He's like,
"Hey, I'm out on a walk. Like, what what
if, you know, what if what if you think
about this? Like what if you thought
about that?" And uh, and then we'll sit
there and we'll chat for an hour. Right.
Just a week ago, I chatted for an hour
from like 9:00 p.m. to actually 9 to
10:30 p.m. West Coast time. that was uh
in central time and just thinking about
strategy and how we how we communicate
and what what things we can like little
tiny levers we can pull and yeah
>> the individual logistics that go into
each one of those different things which
there's there are so many logistics
behind the scenes and I think that's you
know I wish we could communicate more
but we we can't uh but we've got a lot
of things that we're interested in
working on and I'm really looking
forward to it. Do you use AI to help?
>> Yeah, absolutely.
>> Yeah, like Sailor.
>> Uh, yeah, absolutely. The the really the
really neat thing with AI is it just
gives another it accelerates thinking.
>> Mhm.
>> One thing that I've been intrigued with
is like I I could take all the
perspectus from strategies, individual
perpetual preferred offerings, and I
could load them into like a chatbt. So,
I'll take all the perspectives and I'll
load them in and I'll take um I'll take
other bits of pieces of information like
PDFs of different things that are
interesting to me and I I use that as
like a project. So, I go create projects
in chat chat GBT and then it's like okay
I've got all of this information as my
background. Now let's provide let's
think about you know based on assumption
A B C D and um these these different
things
what's the most efficient route or
product that I can create to access this
market or you know what are some markets
that I can access and I mean I've spent
hours on chatbt just like pounding it
>> identifying like different unique um
ideas that's helped accelerate my
thinking and and helped narrow
uh perspective. So that's
where that's kind of how I've used it is
like to to kind of take like these all
these huge ideas and try to like narrow
my focus.
>> Um it's not perfect. Like it's
definitely not perfect and it's not uh
it assumes that there's no friction in
the world.
>> So like you may come up with this great
idea but you actually try to put it in
practice and there's just a ton of
friction in the market. Like
>> the lawyers hate it. the you know it's
too complicated, I can't underwrite it,
you know the all these types of things.
So there's got to be some sort of like
rationality filter that you got to apply
to some of the output that you get from
AI. But I mean it's incredible tool and
it's only getting better.
>> For a regular layman person that's
watching this, all these companies, they
can borrow money at a very cheap rate to
buy more Bitcoin. But for a just a
regular person, I can only buy Bitcoin
with my salary or my savings. Now, how
do I get ahead?
>> I will say I do believe this market is
incredibly young and incredibly early.
So, I think if you're just remotely
close to it now,
>> 10 years down the road, I think
everybody that's here is going to do
fantastically well. Um
>> Oh, I love that.
>> I I'm I'm relatively certain of it. Um
this is not financial advice, but like
Bitcoin is a two trillion two and a half
trillion dollar asset. I think it's
highly likely it goes to 10 trillion and
then highly like it goes to 20 trillion.
And if you think about like what is a
what is a company that's holding 3% of
the network of the Bitcoin network look
like when Bitcoin goes to tr 20 tr is a
20 trillion asset. It's like well uh
that's a company that's holding $700
billion worth of capital at that point
or maybe more like 700$800 billion of
capital. Like there's no there is not
another company in the entire market in
the entire world that's holding that
much capital.
>> So like what is what does the world look
like then?
>> I don't know.
>> No, it's like well how much fixed income
can you issue if you're holding 900 tr
$900 billion of capital? It's like okay
you could go you go issue a billion
dollars a week.
>> Yeah. you can issue a billion dollars a
week of fixed income at 9% interest or
it's like the market the market should
be there
>> because the the risk profile of these
things is like going to be
foundationally different.
>> Do you think countries can do that now?
>> Yes.
>> Right.
>> Are they going to?
>> They should,
>> but they're not yet.
>> Uh they're not yet. I think they can. I
think there's a race to do it.
>> Mhm.
>> Um
>> there is a race. People talk about that,
but like it seems like nobody's doing
anything.
>> Why is the United States one of the most
valuable
countries in the world?
>> Why?
>> They hold the most gold. Money is
incredibly powerful and I think having
control of like a monetary network and a
monetary supply is going to be like
crucial for uh future power of any
country because you you have the ability
to like leverage that monetary base,
right? I think
>> the US has eight times more gold than
the next closest country.
And that has that has led to some of the
US success. Like granted geographically
it's very valuable. You got two big
oceans and you know you got all of those
things. So geographically it's very
valuable but another one of the main
reasons it's valuable is because they
have more money than anybody else.
>> Yeah. And I think they will continue to
be in a position where they have more
money than anybody else unless
other powerful countries
getting this monetary network before you
do and then controlling a majority of
like how that's how that's used or
deployed.
>> Wow. I I think people can take away this
like we are still early. People look at
Bitcoin price and um be like, "Oh my
god, I can't afford one bitcoin. I'm so
so behind.
It's over.
>> Yeah. Nominal bias will always exist.
>> Yeah.
>> Nominal bias of of Bitcoin will always
exist. So there's there's always
opportunity to just get off of zero. And
I think that's my biggest recommendation
to anybody is just get off zero uh and
and have like greater than zero exposure
to this stuff
>> because it's mo like this market is
moving incredibly fast. You look at a
company like Strategy
in In 2020, Strategy had $500 million of
cash.
>> Mhm.
>> They now have $70 billion of Bitcoin.
That's five years. Five years, they've
gone from $500 million of cash to $70
billion of Bitcoin. Like, what does it
look five years from now?
>> We don't know.
>> We We don't know, but it's it's likely
going to be more
>> a lot more. or it could, you know, two,
three, four, five times um into the
future. And they're not stopping.
>> I'm not stopping. Everybody here is not
stopping.
>> They're all plugged into the capital
markets trying to siphon as much capital
out of the traditional financial system
as possible
>> and shove it into Bitcoin.
>> That's a good that's a good analogy.
>> That's that's what we're doing here. And
we're not stopping.
>> My god, I can't sleep now.
>> Yeah. It's like, oh, it's happening
right now 24/7.
>> It's it's happening. There's there's 150
companies that are operating on a
Bitcoin standard today. Uh 5 years ago,
there was one.
>> Five years from now, there's going to be
2,000.
>> What's the world like look like when
2,000 companies are vying for the same
number of coins on the market?
>> Wow.
>> There's competition. It's speeding up.
But it's this like co-option, you know?
It's like co-optition. uh all of these
companies are as the price of Bitcoin
rises, the tide rises for all of them
and they all get more powerful. So, it's
like you get more companies in here that
are doing the same thing. And and props
to Sailor, man. I mean, he's really
written the playbook on this thing. And
I couldn't imagine sitting back and like
watching 150 other companies just start
doing exactly what you're doing. It's
just like incredible to see. And success
breeds more success. Like every
everybody wants to succeed in the world.
I think that will just continue to
continue to permeate. Uh but it just
takes time. It's like a virus.
>> That was such a beautiful conversation.
Thank you, Jeff.
>> Absolutely. Thank you.
>> Yeah. Thanks for having me. and
appreciate it.